Finding Aid for the Edwin S. Shneidman Papers LSC.0385
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Correspondence, Series 2.
  - June 1980., 1980 June. (Box 11, Folder 34)
  - July 1980., 1980 July. (Box 11, Folder 35)
  - August 1980., 1980 August. (Box 11, Folder 36)
  - September '80., 1980 September. (Box 11, Folder 37)
  - October 1980., 1980 October. (Box 11, Folder 38)
  - November 1980., 1980 November. (Box 11, Folder 39)
  - December 1980., 1980 December. (Box 11, Folder 40)
  - January 1981., 1981 January. (Box 11, Folder 41)
  - February 1981., 1981 February. (Box 11, Folder 42)
  - March 1981., 1981 March. (Box 11, Folder 43)
  - April 1981., 1981 April. (Box 11, Folder 44)
  - May 1981., 1981 May. (Box 11, Folder 45)
  - June 1981., 1981 June. (Box 11, Folder 46)
  - July 1981., 1981 July. (Box 11, Folder 47)
  - August 1981., 1981 August. (Box 11, Folder 48)
  - September 1981., 1981 September. (Box 11, Folder 49)
  - October 1981., 1981 October. (Box 11, Folder 50)
  - November 1981., 1981 November. (Box 11, Folder 51)
  - December 1981., 1981 December. (Box 11, Folder 52)
  - January 1982., 1982 January. (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - February 1982., 1982 February. (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - March 1982., 1982 March. (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - April 1982., 1982 April. (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - May 1982., 1982 May. (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - June 1982., 1982 June. (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - July 1982., 1982 July. (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - August 1982., 1982 August. (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - September 1982., 1982 September. (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - October 1982., 1982 October. (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - November 1982., 1982 November. (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - December 1982., 1982 December. (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - Misc. Corres. Received: thank yous, clippings, etc., 1982. (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - Sprague/Shneidman., 1981-1982. (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - Suicide Prevention Pamphlet; responses from Univ. and Coll., 1982. (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - Memorial Cancer Research Foundation of So. Calif. Inc. (Plotkin) (Brotman Mem. Hosp.)., 1976-1977. (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - MS in Thanatology., 1982-1983. (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Ralph K. White., undated. (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Montreal., 1982 October. (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - November planning committee/Neuropsychiatric Institute., 1982. (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - Melville film., 1982 April 26. (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - Loyola Marymount University, Loss, Mourning and Restitution., 1982 July 16-18. (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - City of Hope, cancelled., 1982 March 13. (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - Kean College of New Jersey., 1982 April. (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - San Diego State University., 1982 September 25. (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - Canton, Ohio., 1982 February 27. (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - January 1983., 1983 January. (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - February 1983., 1983 February. (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - March 1983., 1983 March. (Box 12, Folder 29)
  - April 1983., 1983 April. (Box 12, Folder 30)
  - May 1983., 1983 May. (Box 12, Folder 31)
  - June 1983., 1983 June. (Box 12, Folder 32)
  - July 1983., 1983 July. (Box 12, Folder 33)
  - August 1983., 1983 August. (Box 12, Folder 34)
  - September 1983., 1983 September. (Box 12, Folder 35)
  - October 1983., 1983 October. (Box 12, Folder 36)
  - Sylvia Glass, artist., 1983 October. (Box 12, Folder 37)
    Contains slides of artwork.
  - November 1983., 1983 November. (Box 12, Folder 38)
  - December 1983., 1983 December. (Box 12, Folder 39)
  - Dozor., 1983. (Box 12, Folder 40)
  - San Diego Naval Hospital., 1983 April 12. (Box 12, Folder 41)
  - Archives of the History of American Psychology, University of Akron, Ohio., 1983. (Box 12, Folder 42)
  - Note regarding conference at NPI., 1983 November 2. (Box 12, Folder 43)
  - St. Christopher's Hospice., 1983. (Box 12, Folder 44)
  - Visits., 1981-1982. (Box 12, Folder 45)
  - Deaths of Man., 1983. (Box 12, Folder 46)
  - AAS Correspondence., 1980-1983. (Box 12, Folder 47)
  - A. Alvarez., 1977-1978. (Box 12, Folder 48)
  - Santa Barbara., 1983 June 5. (Box 12, Folder 49)
  - Suicide Prevention Training Program., 1983 July 21. (Box 12, Folder 50)
  - West Covina., 1983 June 25. (Box 12, Folder 51)
  - University of Minnesota., 1983 October 20. (Box 12, Folder 52)
  - Western New York, The Suicidal Person., 1983 October 10. (Box 12, Folder 53)
    Includes two audiocassette tapes.
  - Ethical Issues in Clinical Decision-Making, Veteran's Administration, Sepulveda (Los Angeles)., 1983 September 21. (Box 12, Folder 54)
  - Didi Hirsch., 1983 December 14. (Box 12, Folder 55)
  - German (Pending)., 1981-1985. (Box 12, Folder 56)
  - Ben Gurion University (1 of 2)., 1983. (Box 12, Folder 57)
  - Ben Gurion University (2 of 2)., 1983. (Box 12, Folder 58)
  - Psychogeriatric seminar "Thanatology and the Elderly"., 1983 November. (Box 12, Folder 59)
  - Reader's Digest., 1983 November. (Box 12, Folder 60)
  - January 1984., 1984 January. (Box 12, Folder 61)
  - February 1984., 1984 February. (Box 12, Folder 62)
  - March 1984., 1984 March. (Box 12, Folder 63)
  - April 1984., 1984 April. (Box 12, Folder 64)
  - The Suicidal Crisis Center., 1984. (Box 12, Folder 65)
  - Don Siegerson., 1984. (Box 12, Folder 66)
  - D. of S. Correspondence, also permissions., 1984. (Box 12, Folder 67)
  - Blurbs about DofS (Definition of Suicide)., 1984. (Box 12, Folder 68)
  - Radio Show WOAI-CBS., 1984 January 9. (Box 12, Folder 69)
  - Radio Show KABC., 1984 January 12. (Box 12, Folder 70)
  - Thanatology letters re: Colloquium., 1984 Spring. (Box 12, Folder 71)
  - University of Minnesota., 1984 May. (Box 12, Folder 72)
  - Correspondence (1 of 2)., 1984. (Box 12, Folder 73)
  - Correspondence (2 of 2)., 1984. (Box 12, Folder 74)
  - Tokumitsu and Sachiko Shirai -- Restricted., 1984 September 26. (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - CSSS Pepper, Stephen C. -- Restricted., 1964-1965. (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Naegele, Kaspar D. (Dr.) -- Restricted., 1963. (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Chapter Burton - The Threat of Dying & Behavior Change-Behavior Constancy -- Restricted., 1975 February. (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence -- Restricted., 1984-1985. (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Leenaars -- Restricted., 1984-1985. (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence 1985 Jan-June -- Restricted., 1985 January-June. (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - July 1985 -- Restricted., 1985 July. (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - August 1985 -- Restricted., 1985 August. (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - September 1985 -- Restricted., 1985 September. (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - October 1985 -- Restricted., 1985 October. (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - November 1985 -- Restricted., 1985 November. (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - December 1985 -- Restricted., 1985 December. (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - Judy Angel/Fund Raising, Nan Roberts -- Restricted., 1983-1985. (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Kalle Achte, MD -- Restricted., 1985 May 12-14. (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - University of Santa Clara -- Restricted., 1985. (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - University letters, uncategorized -- Restricted., 1970-1986. (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Uncategorized correspondence -- Restricted., 1985. (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Society for Personology -- Restricted., 1985. (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - January 1986 -- Restricted., 1986 January. (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - February 1986 -- Restricted., 1986 February. (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - March 1986 -- Restricted., 1986 March. (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - April 1986 -- Restricted., 1986 April. (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - May 1986 -- Restricted., 1986 May. (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - June 1986 -- Restricted., 1986 June. (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - July 1986 -- Restricted., 1986 July. (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - August 1986 -- Restricted., 1986 August. (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - September 1986 -- Restricted., 1986 September. (Box 13, Folder 28)
  - October 1986 -- Restricted., 1986 October. (Box 13, Folder 29)
  - Aspen July 14-16, 1986 Menninger Suicide Conference -- Restricted., 1986 July 14-16. (Box 13, Folder 30)
  - Kaiser Permanente -- Restricted., 1986 June 12. (Box 13, Folder 31)
  - NIMH -- Restricted., 1986 May 8-9. (Box 13, Folder 32)
  - New York Times -- Restricted., 1986 June 4. (Box 13, Folder 33)
  - Kings College Ontario -- Restricted., 1986 June. (Box 13, Folder 34)
  - Harvard-Cambridge Hosp., Boston -- Restricted., 1986 January. (Box 13, Folder 35)
  - V.A. Hospital -- Restricted., 1986 January 21. (Box 13, Folder 36)
  - Psychiatry Series Colloq. -- Restricted., 1986 February 27. (Box 13, Folder 37)
  - Master Lecture, Washington DC -- Restricted., 1986 August 22-26. (Box 13, Folder 38)
  - US Navy -- Restricted., 1986 September 26. (Box 13, Folder 39)
  - Samaritans Boston -- Restricted., 1986 October 3-4. (Box 13, Folder 40)
  - November 1986 -- Restricted., 1986 November. (Box 13, Folder 41)
  - December 1986 -- Restricted., 1986 December. (Box 13, Folder 42)
  - January 1987 -- Restricted., 1987 January. (Box 13, Folder 43)
  - February 1987 -- Restricted., 1987 February. (Box 13, Folder 44)
  - March 1987 -- Restricted., 1987 March. (Box 13, Folder 45)
  - April 1987 -- Restricted., 1987 April. (Box 13, Folder 46)
  - May 1987 -- Restricted., 1987 May. (Box 13, Folder 47)
  - June 1987 -- Restricted., 1987 June. (Box 13, Folder 48)
  - July 1987 -- Restricted., 1987 July. (Box 13, Folder 49)
  - August 1987 -- Restricted., 1987 August. (Box 13, Folder 50)
  - September 1987 -- Restricted., 1987 September. (Box 13, Folder 51)
  - October 1987 -- Restricted., 1987 October. (Box 13, Folder 52)
  - November 1987 -- Restricted., 1987 November. (Box 13, Folder 53)
  - December 1987 -- Restricted., 1987 December. (Box 13, Folder 54)
  - Restricted correspondence -- Restricted., 1987. (Box 13, Folder 55)
  - Letters of Recommendation and Reference -- Restricted., 1985-1987. (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Regina Ryan Correspondence -- Restricted., 1986-1987. (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - "Therefore I must Kill Myself" -- Restricted., 1981. (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - VA Palliative Treatment Center -- Restricted., 1985. (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Beverly Hills Medical Center -- Restricted., 1985 August 20. (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - CASBS - Stanford -- Restricted., 1985. (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Dying, Denying and Willing the Obligatory -- Restricted., 1982-1986. (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Martin Luther King Hospital, Grand Rounds -- Restricted., 1985 May 28. (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Handicapped Physicians -- Restricted., 1985 March 26. (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - LA Times Book Review -- Restricted., 1985 May 29. (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Death: Current Perspectives III Mayfield Correspondence and originals -- Restricted., 1983-1984. (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Stillion Intro - ESS Death Education -- Restricted., 1983 November and 1984 March. (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - On Abolishing Death (Pending) -- Restricted., 1982 April and May. (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Encyclopedia of Psych. Revised. -- Restricted., 1982 and 1986. (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Herson Chapter in Recent Developments in Adol. Psy -- Restricted., 1985 December. (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Psychology Today -- Restricted., 1986. (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Stanford National Legal Center for Medically Dependent & Disabled, Inc. -- Restricted., 1987 April 2-4. (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Mardi Gras -- Restricted., 1987. (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Atascadero (canceled) -- Restricted., 1987 February 4-5. (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - UCLA Dr. Viktor Frankel Introduction -- Restricted., 1987 October 18. (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Pepperdine University -- Restricted., 1987 November 4. (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Suicide Prevention Workshop, Dept. of Psychology -- Restricted., 1987 March 18. (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Youth Suicide Maine -- Restricted., 1987 May. (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - Cable News -- Restricted., 1987 February 23. (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - Valley Presbyterian Hosp. -- Restricted., 1987 July 14. (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - Case conference adolescent services -- Restricted., 1987 August 20. (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - Glendale Adventist Medical Center -- Restricted., 1987 June 18. (Box 14, Folder 27)
  - Forward Mamuro Iga's book -- Restricted., 1985 May 16. (Box 14, Folder 28)
  - Notes and correspondence -- Restricted., undated. (Box 14, Folder 29)
  - Uncategorized correspondence -- Restricted., 1983-1987. (Box 14, Folder 30)
  - Cedars-Sinai -- Restricted., 1988 January 18. (Box 14, Folder 31)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence -- Restricted., 1970s. (Box 14, Folder 32)
  - APA Task Force on Treatment of Psychiatric Disorders -- Restricted., 1987 April 27. (Box 14, Folder 33)
  - Miscellaneous correspondence -- Restricted., 1987-1988. (Box 14, Folder 34)
  - Aphorisms, white paper -- Restricted., 1988 December. (Box 14, Folder 35)
  - Patient letters [name withheld] (1 of 4) -- Restricted., 1985-1987. (Box 14, Folder 36)
  - Patient letters [name withheld] (2 of 4) -- Restricted., 1984-1986. (Box 14, Folder 37)
  - Patient letters [name withheld] (3 of 4) -- Restricted., 1985. (Box 14, Folder 38)
  - Patient letters [name withheld] (4 of 4) -- Restricted., 1983-1985. (Box 14, Folder 39)
  - Patient correspondence [name withheld] -- Restricted., 1986-1987. (Box 14, Folder 40)
  - Patient correspondence "Residue" [name withheld] -- Restricted., 1985-1992. (Box 14, Folder 41)
    Includes photos of patient, pre and post-suicide attempt, and Shneidman.
  - Patient Mental Health Services Report, 1990 [name withheld]; Shneidman notes; "Castro" -- Restricted., 1990 October 15. (Box 14, Folder 42)
  - HAM Memorial -- Restricted., 1988 October. (Box 14, Folder 43)
  - Notre Dame -- Restricted., 1988 May 26-27. (Box 14, Folder 44)
  - Janet McCord -- Restricted., 1990s. (Box 14, Folder 45)
    Includes photographs.
  - AAS-CHI-25th -- Restricted., 1992. (Box 14, Folder 46)
  - Kalman Kaplan -- Restricted., 1993 July and August. (Box 14, Folder 47)
  - Bradbury -- Restricted., 1992 October. (Box 14, Folder 48)
  - Garcia vs. People -- Restricted., 1994. (Box 14, Folder 49)
  - Ev (Evelyn) -- Restricted., 1988 November. (Box 14, Folder 50)
  - APA Iowa Comment -- Restricted., 1993. (Box 14, Folder 51)
  - M. David RVDD -- Restricted., 1999. (Box 14, Folder 52)
  - Lester, Theories of Suicide and Attempted Suicide -- Restricted., 1991. (Box 14, Folder 53)
  - Hyatt 1st LT -- Restricted., 1993-1994. (Box 14, Folder 54)
  - Stuart Miller -- Restricted., undated. (Box 14, Folder 55)
  - NIMH -- Restricted., 1990. (Box 14, Folder 56)
  - FFPR (Foundation Fund's Prize for Research)., 1988-1989. (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Foreword to APA Suicidal Patient., 1989 September. (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - Antoon's chapter., 1989-1990. (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - Foreword-Berman., 1990 November 9. (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Bonger's Chapter., 1990 and 1992. (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Mr. and Mrs. Strauss., 1989 July and September. (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - ISL (The Indian Summer of Life)., 1988. (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Pain & Aging., 1993 and 1994. (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - Mary Herzog dissertation., 1992-1995. (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - Israel., 1995. (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Vincent Foster suicide., 1993. (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - Clues to suicide, revisited., 1994. (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Emeritus Group., 1988-1991. (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Kessel, Neil., 1981 and 1997. (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence., 1992-1993. (Box 15, Folder 15)
  - Promotion., 1996. (Box 15, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence with publishers., 1994-1996. (Box 15, Folder 17)
  - Letters., ca. 1990s. (Box 15, Folder 18)
  - David Morris., 1993 March-April. (Box 15, Folder 19)
  - Evelyn Hooker., 1996-1998. (Box 15, Folder 20)
    Includes photographs of Shneidman.
  - Jeff Kropf., 1997-1998. (Box 15, Folder 21)
  - Akron archives., 1991 March-April. (Box 15, Folder 22)
  - Death: Current Perspectives., 1992-1994. (Box 15, Folder 23)
  - HAM Award., 1995 May and 1996 June. (Box 15, Folder 24)
  - Judith Gleba., 1996. (Box 15, Folder 25)
  - Christiana Morgan., 1997 June. (Box 15, Folder 26)
  - US Navy., 1996-1997. (Box 15, Folder 27)
  - Uncategorized correspondence (1 of 2)., 1990s. (Box 15, Folder 28)
  - Uncategorized correspondence (2 of 2)., 1990s. (Box 15, Folder 29)
  - Terry Maltsberger., 1992-1993. (Box 15, Folder 30)
  - KAM (Karl Menninger, MD)., 1998. (Box 15, Folder 31)
  - Samaritans., 1997-1998. (Box 15, Folder 32)
  - Inman Diary chapter., 1994. (Box 15, Folder 33)
  - Douglas Jacobs chapter., 1989 January 9. (Box 15, Folder 34)
  - Obit (Shneidman's self obit)., undated. (Box 15, Folder 35)
  - Book distribution-marketing., 2001. (Box 15, Folder 36)
  - Permissions - Comprehending Suicide., 2000. (Box 15, Folder 37)
  - Vancouver., 1990 October 29. (Box 15, Folder 38)
  - Santa Barbara., 1990 November 2-3. (Box 15, Folder 39)
  - North Carolina., 1989 March 9-10. (Box 15, Folder 40)
  - Louisville., 1989 March 7. (Box 15, Folder 41)
  - Correspondence, miscellaneous., 1994. (Box 15, Folder 42)
  - Uncategorized correspondence., 1988. (Box 15, Folder 43)
  - Uncategorized correspondence., 1989. (Box 15, Folder 44)
  - Psychache book., 1992. (Box 15, Folder 45)
  - AO - APA Contract., 1999-2000. (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Encyclopedia Britannica., 1997. (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Announcement., undated. (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, uncategorized., 2000s. (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - Uncategorized correspondence and notes., 1950s-1960s. (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Uncategorized correspondence and notes (1 of 2)., 1970s. (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Uncategorized correspondence and notes (2 of 2)., 1970s. (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Uncategorized correspondence and notes., 1980s. (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Uncategorized correspondence and notes., 1990s. (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Uncategorized correspondence and notes., 2000s. (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Uncategorized correspondence and notes., undated. (Box 16, Folder 12)
    Includes photograph copy of psychologists, including Sigmund Freud and colleagues.
  - Uncategorized correspondence and notes (1 of 3)., 1970s-1990s. (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Uncategorized correspondence and notes (2 of 3)., 1970s-1990s. (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - Uncategorized correspondence and notes (3 of 3)., 1970s-1990s. (Box 16, Folder 15)
- ESS Publications, Series 3.
  - Bibliography used as checklist., 1943 - 1991. (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Publications., 1940s. (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Publications., 1940s. (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - Publications., 1950s. (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Publications., 1960s. (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Publications., 1960s. (Box 19, Folder 6)
  - Publications., 1961. (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Publications., 1962. (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Publications., 1963. (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - O --> D., 1963. (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Publications., 1964. (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Publications., 1965. (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Publications., 1966. (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Publications., 1967. (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Publications., 1968. (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - Publications., 1969. (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - Publications., 1970s. (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - Shneidman, Edwin S. publication file., ca. 1970s. (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - Publications., 1970 - 1972. (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - Publications., 1970 - 1972. (Box 19, Folder 20)
  - Publications., 1974. (Box 19, Folder 21)
  - Publications., 1975. (Box 19, Folder 22)
  - Publications., 1976 - 1979. (Box 19, Folder 23)
  - Publications (1 of 3)., 1980s. (Box 19, Folder 24)
  - Publications (2 of 3)., 1980s. (Box 19, Folder 25)
  - Publications (3 of 3)., 1980s. (Box 19, Folder 26)
  - Misc. ESS Writings., ca 1960s - 1980s. (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - ESS Articles., 1960s - 1980s. (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Publications., 1980 - 1983. (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Publications & Speeches., 1984 - 1985. (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Publications., 1986. (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Psych Approach to S., 1987. (Box 20, Folder 6)
  - Publications., 1988. (Box 20, Folder 7)
  - ISL., 1989. (Box 20, Folder 8)
  - Publications (1 of 3)., 1990s. (Box 20, Folder 9)
  - Publications (2 of 3)., 1990s. (Box 20, Folder 10)
  - Publications (3 of 3)., 1990s. (Box 20, Folder 11)
  - ESS misc. pubs., 1970s - 1990s. (Box 20, Folder 12)
  - S as P, PA., 1993 - 1994. (Box 20, Folder 13)
  - n.d. or non-pub 1 of 2., Undated. (Box 20, Folder 14)
  - n.d. or non-pub 2 of 2., Undated. (Box 20, Folder 15)
  - Reprints., 1950s. (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - Reprints 1 of 4., 1960s. (Box 20, Folder 17)
  - Reprints 2 of 4., 1960s. (Box 20, Folder 18)
  - Reprints 3 of 4., 1960s. (Box 20, Folder 19)
  - Reprints 4 of 4., 1960s. (Box 20, Folder 20)
  - Reprints., 1970s. (Box 20, Folder 21)
  - Reprints., 1980s. (Box 20, Folder 22)
  - Reprints., 1990s. (Box 20, Folder 23)
  - Reprints., Undated. (Box 20, Folder 24)
  - Assorted ESS articles., 1940s - 1970s. (Box 21, Folder 1)
    Includes On the Deromantization of Death, The Psychological Autopsy, The Psychological Bulletin
  - ESS publications., 1940s - 1960s. (Box 21, Folder 2)
    Includes MAPS and other assessment materials, Some Reflections on Death and Dying, The Logic of Moby-Dick
  - ESS articles., 1940s & 1950s. (Box 21, Folder 3)
    Includes Stanwix and the Baron (unpublished fiction), MAPS and other assessment materials
  - ESS Published Works., 1950s & 1980s. (Box 21, Folder 4)
    Includes suicide articles and MAPS materials
  - E. Shneidman reprints., 1950s - 1980s. (Box 21, Folder 5)
    Includes suicide articles, projective technique articles, Sleep and Self- Destruction
  - Assorted ESS Non-Fiction and Fiction., 1950s - 1980s. (Box 21, Folder 6)
    Includes poetry, The Suicidal Logic of Cesare Pavese, Commentary on Szasz's "The Ethics of Suicide", thanatology program proposal
  - Various ESS publications., 1950s - 1970s. (Box 21, Folder 7)
    Includes suicide articles, research methodology articles, Orientations Toward Death: A Vital Aspect of the Study of Lives
  - Shneidman publications/articles., 1950s - 1970s. (Box 21, Folder 8)
    Includes suicide articles, interview with ESS, The Deaths of Herman Melville
  - Assorted ESS articles., 1950s & 1960s. (Box 21, Folder 9)
    Includes lecture papers, Suicide and the Aged, A Survey of Attempted and Committed Suicide with Special Attention to Veteran Status
  - Assorted ESS articles., 1950s & 1960s. (Box 21, Folder 10)
    Includes The Suicide Prevention Center of Los Angeles, Suicidal Phenomena, A Socio-Psychological Investigation of Suicide
  - ESS Publications., 1960s - 1980s. (Box 21, Folder 11)
    Includes Projective Techniques, Melville & Hawthorne in the Berkshires, Essays in Self-Destruction
  - ESS publications., 1960s - 1980s. (Box 21, Folder 12)
    Includes The Suicidal Logic of Cesare Pavese, draft of Some Thoughts on Grief and Mourning, Suicide, Sleep, and Death
  - Assorted ESS publications., 1960s - 1980s. (Box 21, Folder 13)
    Includes an annotated bibliography for Suicide Notes, Orientations Toward Death, draft of a Psychological Autopsy of Malcolm Melville's Death
  - Assorted ESS publications., 1960s - 1980s. (Box 21, Folder 14)
    Includes A Bibliography of Suicide Notes, Death is Alive and Well at Harvard, Projections on a Triptych; or a Hagiology for Our Time
  - Assorted ESS publications., 1960s - 1980s. (Box 21, Folder 15)
    Includes Aspects of the Personological System of Henry A. Murray, Projective Techniques, The Suicidal Logic of Cesare Pavese, "Suicide" and "Suicidology"
  - Misc. articles by ESS., 1960s - 1980s. (Box 21, Folder 16)
    Includes drafts of the following articles: Some Essentials of Suicide and Some Implications for Response, draft of The Los Angeles Suicide Prevention Center: A Report of Public Service Feasibilities, draft of Logical Content Analysis, draft of Some Aspects of Psychotherapy with Dying Persons,
  - Assorted ESS published articles., 1960s & 1970s. (Box 21, Folder 17)
    Includes The Enemy, draft of Psycho-Logic: An Explanation of Argument, Investigations of Equivocal Suicides
  - ESS papers (carbon copies)., 1960s & 1970s. (Box 21, Folder 18)
    Includes Suicide and its Prevention, Orientations Toward Death as an Aspect of the Study of Lives, Suicidal Phenomena: Their Definition and Classification